Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
- PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1927-1966; Series IX; 1' (3 boxes)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 349)
    - Gertrud Hindemith-W. T. Brown autograph letter signed/Eng Christmas card, Dec 1957
    - Gertrud Hindemith-J. Moran Myer autograph letter signed/Eng Christmas card, Dec 1957
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, 6 Dec 1957
  - Personal Correspondence, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 350)
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter unsigned/English card photocopy, 10 Jan 1958
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter unsigned/English card photocopy, 23 Jan 1958
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 3 Feb 1958
      Reel I/279-280
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 6 Feb 1958
      Reel I/281-82
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds typed letter signed/English, 6 Feb 1958
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 11 Feb 1958
      Reel I/288-289
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 24 Feb 1958
      Reel I/122-125
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter unsigned/English, 25 Feb 1958
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 27 Feb 1958
      Reel I/290
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 12 Mar 1958
      Reel I/291-93
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 14 Mar 1958
      Reel I/294-95
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English on typed copy of L. Bernstein's letter to W. Schulthess, 22 Mar 1958
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 30 Mar 1958
      Reel I/298
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 5 Apr 1958
      Reel I/126-128
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 16 June 1958
      Reel I/299
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English card, 27 June 1958
      Reel I/300
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 22 July 1958
      Reel I/301-02
    - Gertrud Hindemith-K. Bauer typed letter signed/English photocopy, 23 July 1958
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 24 July 1958
      Reel I/129-132
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 10 Sept 1958
      Reel I/133-134
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, Oct 1958
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 25 Nov 1958
      Reel I/135-137
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1958
    - Gertrud Hindemith-G & R. Donovan autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, 9 Dec 1958
    - Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer autograph letter signed/Ger & English, 15 Dec 1958
      Reel I/171-172
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 23 Dec 1958
      Reel I/303
    - Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer autograph letter signed/German, 28? Dec 1958
      Reel I/138
  - Personal Correspondence, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 351)
    - Gertrud Hindemith-E. J. O'Meara autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Jan 1959
    - Gertrud Hindemith-J. Moran Myer autograph letter signed/English Christmas card photocopy, Jan 1959
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 1 Jan 1959
      Reel I/139
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 10 Jan 1959
      Reel I/304-06
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-L & O. Cox autograph letter signed/English card, 10 Feb 1959
      Reel I/173
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-L. Feist (AMP) autograph letter signed/English embroidered card, Mar 1959
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss autograph letter signed/English 10 Mar; order for Hymnal sent to Paul Hindemith 18 May + O. Noss memo 15 Mar, 1959
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 20 Mar 1959
      Reel I/140-141
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English 17 Apr + L. Noss-Schulthess 23 Mar & response 28 Mar, 1959
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 19 Apr 1959
      Reel I/311-314
    - L. Noss-Paul Hindemith, 19 Apr, 11 May 1959
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English 2 cards, 1959
      Reel I/315-16
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss typed letter signed/English 5 June + L. Noss-Paul Hindemith 11 June, 1959
      Reel I/317-18
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss typed letter signed/English 17 July + L. Noss-Paul Hindemith 24 July, 1959
      Reel I/319-322
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English card, Sept 1959
      Reel I/174
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-L. Noss autograph letter signed/English 3 cards, 19 Sept 1959
      Reel I/175-177
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss autograph letter signed/English 20 Sept + Joseph Iadone-Gertrud & Paul Hindemith 11 Sept, L. Noss-J. Iadone 12 Oct, 1959
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 28 Sept 1959
      Reel I/327-28
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 30 Sept 1959
      Reel I/329
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 2 Nov 1959
      Reel I/330
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith+Benny Goodman-O. Cox, 3? Nov 1959
      Reel I/178
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English Christmas 2 cards, Dec 1959
    - Paul Hindemith-W. H. Dunham autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1959
    - Gertrud Hindemith-J. Moran Myer autograph letter signed/English Christmas card photocopy, Dec 1959
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 5? Dec 1959
      Reel I/142
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 7 Dec 1959
      Reel I/331
  - Personal Correspondence, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 352)
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Feist autograph letter signed/English card, Jan 1960? 1960
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox autograph letter signed/English 2 cards, 4 Jan 1960
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-L. Noss typed & autograph letter signed with outline of Yale concert for 19 Feb, 7 Jan 1960
      Reel I/181-183
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 15 Jan 1960
      Reel I/143-144
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 23 Jan 1960
      Reel I/332
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 24 Jan 1960
      Reel I/333
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 26 Jan 1960
      Reel I/334
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English card from Spain, 10 Feb 1960
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Noss autograph letter signed/English tiny card, 19 Feb 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-P & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English Greeting card, 22 Feb 1960
      Reel I/335-38
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss autograph letter signed/English card, 7 Mar 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-C & E. Grumman autograph letter signed/English photocard of Gertrud & Paul Hindemith at pier in New York, 16 Mar 1960
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 28 May 1960
      Reel I/145-148
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 3 June 1960
      Reel I/339
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 7 June 1960
      Reel I/149
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L & L. Noss typed letter signed/English + part of Vevey brochure, 19 June 1960
      Reel I/340
    - Paul Hindemith-R. Donovan undated enclosure card with A Composer's World, 1960
  - Personal Correspondence, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 353)
    - Paul Hindemith-L. Noss telegram/English, 25 July 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 3 Aug 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss autograph letter signed/English, 4 Aug 1960
    - Isabel Wilder-O. Noss typed letter signed, 10 Aug 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-Noss autograph letter signed/English card, 12 Aug 1960
    - O. Cox-Paul Hindemith autograph letter signed/English + Time magazine clipping, 11 Oct 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 31 Oct 1960
    - Paul Hindemith-Thornton/Isabel Wilder Christmas card, Dec 1960
    - Paul Hindemith-G & R. Donovan Christmas card with notes, Dec 1960
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss 2 cards, Dec 1960
    - Paul Hindemith-O & L. Noss Christmas card 3-part canon, Dec 1960
    - Paul Hindemith-L & O. Cox autograph letter signed/English photocard E. Speidel Hamburg, 21 Dec 1960
  - Personal Correspondence, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 354)
    - Gertrud Hindemith-J. Moran Myer autograph letter signed/English Christmas card photocopy, Jan 1961
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 15 Jan 1961
      Reel I/347-348
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 10 Mar 1961
      Reel I/152
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English 3 cards, 29 Apr 1961
      Reel I/349-352
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 2 July 1961
      Reel I/353
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 3 July 1961
      Reel I/153
    - Gertrud Hindemith-T. Wilder typed letter signed/English, 8 July 1961
      Reel I/354
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss telephone message English, 1961
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English + card, 14 Aug 1961
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 17 Oct 1961
      Reel I/357
    - Gertrud Hindemith-I. Wilder typed letter signed/English, 5 Nov 1961
      Reel I/358
    - Gertrud Hindemith-I. Wilder autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1961
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-G & R. Donovan autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1961
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1961
    - Paul Hindemith-customs declaration-L & O. Cox, 1 Dec 1961
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 10 Dec 1961
      Reel I/359-360
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 11 Dec 1961
      Reel I/361
    - Paul Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English + Beethovenhalle concert in Bonn program, 11 Dec 1961
  - Personal Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 355)
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 20 Feb 1962
      Reel I/363
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 1 Mar 1962
      Reel I/364-367
    - L. Noss-Gertrud & Paul Hindemith typed letter unsigned, 1962
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 3 Mar 1962
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 6 Mar 1962
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 21 Mar 1962
      Reel I/368
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 22 Mar 1962
      Reel I/369-370
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox typed letter signed/English, 28 Mar 1962
      Reel I/37I/372
    - Gertrud Hindemith-T. Wilder typed letter signed/English, 9 Apr 1962
      Reel I/373
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 1 May 1962
      Reel I/374-378
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 23 May 1962
      Reel I/158-159
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English 2 photocopies, 17 July 1962
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1962
    - Gertrud Hindemith-J. Moran Myer autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1962
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1962
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/Eng, 6 Dec 1962
      Reel I/379-380
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-G & R. Donovan autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Jan 1963
      Reel I/184
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 20 Feb 1963
      Reel I/381
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 22 Feb 1963
      Reel I/160
    - Paul Hindemith-C & E. Grumman autograph letter signed/English, May 1963
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Cox autograph letter signed/English, 14 June 1963
      Reel I/161
    - Paul Hindemith-L. Feist autograph letter signed/English, 19 July 1963
    - Paul Hindemith-L. Feist autograph letter signed/English, 15 Sept 1963
  - Personal Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 23, Folder 356)
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R. Schönthal autograph letter signed/English, Apr 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-C. Miller autograph letter signed/English, Apr 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English, 7 Apr 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-H & H. Boatwright autograph letter signed/English photocopy, 23 Apr 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English, 20 Apr 1964
      Reel I/382-387
    - Gertrud Hindemith-W. T. Brown autograph letter signed/English, 26 Apr 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English + letters from O. Noss, L. Noss, George Lam, 29 Sept 1964
      Reel I/388-394
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss typed letter signed/English, 6 Oct 1964
      Reel I/395-396
    - B. Shepard-Gertrud Hindemith typed letter unsigned, 19 Nov 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1964
    - L. Noss-Gertrud Hindemith typed letter unsigned/English 18, Dec 1964
    - Gertrud Hindemith-G & R. Donovan autograph letter signed/English 2 cards, Jan 1965
    - Gertrud Hindemith-E. J. O'Meara autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Jan 1965
    - Gertrud Hindemith-I. Wilder autograph letter signed/English 2 cards, 9 Jan 1965
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English + L. Noss reply typed letter unsigned card & letter, 26 Jan 1965
      Reel I/400-404
    - Gertrud Hindemith-Brooks Shepard autograph letter signed/English, 31 Jan 1965
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss typed letter signed/English, 8 July 1965
      Reel I/406-407
    - Gertrud Hindemith-B. Shepard typed letter signed/English, 25 July 1965
      Reel I/408-409
    - Gertrud Hindemith-R & B. Simonds autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1965
    - Gertrud Hindemith-E. J. O'Meara autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1965
    - Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss autograph letter signed/English Christmas card, Dec 1965
    - O. Noss-Gertrud Hindemith typed letter unsigned/English, 14 Oct 1966
- MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS, 1940-1988; Series X; 3.5' (8 boxes)
  Series X comprises miscellaneous materials, including complete copies of all official documents pertaining to Paul Hindemith's appointment to the Yale University faculty, his leave of absence to lecture at Harvard University, and his resignation in 1953. Other folders in this series contain duplicate Christmas cards and holograph scenarios for two unproduced ballets: The Children's Crusade" and "The Parable of the Blind," prepared for Leonid Massine and George Balachine.
  Additional folders in this series include class exercises and student projects (Folders 363-373); lists of writings, speeches, and lectures deposited in the Hindemith Institute in Frankfurt (381); information on the founding of the Institute and Foundation; correspondence relating to the Yale Hindemith Collection; and a listing by the Deutsches Rundfunkarchiv of Paul Hindemith as a conductor and soloist in recorded and live performances in Europe (399).
  - Official Yale Documents, 1940-1945 (Box 23, Folder 357)
    - D. S. Smith-President Charles Seymour photocopy, 11 Jan 1940
    - Provost E. Furniss-President Charles Seymour photocopy, 12 Jan 1940
    - President Seymour-D. S. Smith photocopy, 16 Jan 1940
    - D. S. Smith-Oberlander Trust, 23 Jan 1940
    - Yale News release photocopy, 26 Mar 1940
    - re: Paul Hindemith's appointment as Visiting Professor photocopy, 13, 27 Apr 1940
    - Yale News release re: appointment of Paul Hindemith & R. Kirkpatrick photocopy, 1 May 1940
    - Howland Prize award photocopy, 20 Nov 1940
    - R. D. French-President Seymour photocopy, 16 Jan 1941
    - President Seymour-Paul Hindemith photocopy, 22 Jan 1941
    - Provost Furniss-Paul Hindemith photocopy, 28 Jan 1941
    - D. S. Smith-President Seymour + reply of same date, 29 Jan 1941
    - Paul Hindemith's appointment as Professor photocopy, 1, 8, 11 Feb 1941
    - M. Bartholomew-President Seymour + reply, 15 Feb 1941
    - Yale University School of Music secretary-Current Biography, 13 Sept 1941
    - M. Paranov-B. Simonds, 21 Mar 1942
    - Yale University School of Music Alumni Bulletins, Mar-Dec 1942
    - Yale University School of Music Alumni Bulletin, June 1943
    - Paul Hindemith's reappointment as Professor, 10 Apr, 13 May 1944
    - Yale University School of Music Alumni Bulletin, May 1944
    - Yale University School of Music Alumni Bulletin, Apr 1945
    - W. Naumburg-B. Simonds + reply, 26 Nov 1945
  - Official Yale Documents, 1946-1953 (Box 23, Folder 358)
    - Yale University School of Music Alumni Bulletin, Aug 1946
    - Provost Furniss-Paul Hindemith typed letter signed, 25 Sept 1946
    - Paul Hindemith's appointment as Battell Professor typed letter unsigned, 7 Feb, 19 Apr 1947
    - telegram R. Kendall-B. Simonds + reply typed letter unsigned, 31 Oct 1947
    - M. Gulick-B. Simonds re: Baker's Dictionary typed letter signed, 12 Nov 1947
    - B. Simonds-Provost Furniss re: Paul Hindemith leave of absence to lecture at Harvard, 9, 11, 12 Mar 1948
    - B. Simonds-B. Raisen + initial 2 Jan letter, 7 Jan 1949
    - B. Simonds-Provost Furniss, 11 Jan, 12 Feb 1949
    - T. Merritt-B. Simonds + reply; B. Simonds-Provost Furniss; corporation vote, 20, 21 Apr, 5, 14 May 1949
    - B. Simonds-Provost Furniss re: Paul Hindemith teaching in Yale & Zurich, 26, 27 July, 11, 20 Aug 1950
    - S. Shulman's request re: opus 10 quartet, 8 Sept 1950
    - telegram Music Lovers Society, San Francisco, 19 Oct 1950
    - Apr Paul Hindemith Leave request to teach in Zurich 1951-52, 10, 14 1951
    - R. Faith-Yale University School of Music re: Traditional Harmony, 10 Sept 1951
    - A. Hackett-Yale University School of Music re: lessons, 15 Nov 1951
    - Provost Furniss-Paul Hindemith re: resignation photocopy, 15 Dec 1952
    - re: resignation accepted by corporation, 10 January 1953
  - undated (Box 23, Folder 359)
    - Plaque presented to C & E. Grumman
    - Inexpensive illustration by Art Pub. Co. Chi. in color of man holding kithara, standing beside woman in green, looking at two swans in pool - this is pasted on a wooden back. The picture bears evidence that an additional background drawing in ink was imposed on the original. On the reverse side is written autograph letter signed:
    - Recent Visitors of R. I.:
    - Paul Hindemith, composing a Sonata for Kythara
    - Gertrud Hindemith, already enjoying this piece
    - Two swans, waiting for the next piece, a duet Schwanengesang
    - A price of 2/25 cents is marked in pencil
  - [Untitled] (Box 23, Folder 360)
    - Duplicate Christmas Cards + 10 pages of photocopy property of Mr & Mrs John T. Lowe in German
    - 15 pages of photocopy property of Lorraine Crittenden Atkinson
    - Jigsaw puzzle to L. Noss 1940s
  - Envelopes autographed on backside (Box 23, Folder 361)
  - Unproduced Ballet Scenarios, 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 362)
    - Der Kinderkreuzzug holograph scenario + holograph notes, abridged and paraphrased translation of scenario by L. Noss, 1939
    - Das Gleichnis von der Blinden Holograph scenario + holograph notes and English scenario prepared by L. Noss., 1940
    - Class Exercises, Individual Student Projects, 1940
  - Reading Material for History of Theory class (Box 24, Folder 363)
    [translated into English by Paul Hindemith]
    - Boethius: from De Institutione Musica Book I
    - Part II of Scholia Enchiriadis
    - Odo of Cluny: from Enchiridion Musices
    - Guido of Arezzo: Prologus Antiphonarii Sui
    - Cassiodorus: Institutiones, Chapter V
    - Jacopo de Liège: Speculum Musicae, Prohemium/Book VII
  - [Untitled] (Box 24, Folder 364)
    - Class-composed Piano Piece; class projects from Tanglewood from H. Fromm, 1940-1941
    - Class Notes of Lorraine Crittendon [Mrs. E. R. Atkinson], 1941
  - [Untitled] (Box 24, Folder 365)
    - Etudes for Violinists, fragments, 1941-42
    - Student Compositions by J. Dunlap, M. Levine, D. S. Holt, R. Vinitsky, H.-J. Rudas, L. Hemingway, G. Lam, 1942
  - [Untitled] (Box 24, Folder 366)
    - Analysis of Monteverdi: Orfeo by J. Moran Myer, 1942
    - Compositions by R. Vinitsky, H. Rudas, A. Etler, exercises by J. Moran Myer; "Amours de Marie" by P. H. (J. W. ), 1943
    - Composition by S. K. Tam, 1944
  - Class projects, book reviews, Traditional Harmony supplementary exercises, class notes in History of Theory by C. Miller, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 367)
  - Degree Requirements, articles, Traditional Harmony II solutions, Exercises in Fugue Writing by C. Miller, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 368)
  - [Untitled] (Box 24, Folder 369)
    - Student Composition program, 10 March 1947
    - Choral piece by J. Dunlap, 1947
    - Choral pieces by D. Kraehenbuehl, J. Cowell, 1948
    - Student papers by H. Blumenfeld, D. Kraehenbuehl, 1948
    - Variations by L. Berkowitz, (1948 or earlier)
    - Fugue writing exercise, 1940s
  - [Untitled] (Box 24, Folder 370)
    - Class notes by W. Moffat, G. Welsh, 1950
    - F. Lewin composition for Paul Hindemith's 55th birthday + 2 tape recordings, 1950
  - History of Theory class notes by M. F. Withrow, W. Eckert, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 371)
  - Student paper by S. di Bonaventura; photocopy of String Trio class project, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 372)
  - B. Quashen: compositions & class notes, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 373)
  - Paul Hindemith Biographical Data excluding life in the USA, 1935-1963 (Box 25, Folder 374)
  - Paul Hindemith in the United States, a Chronological Record, 1937-1963 (Box 25, Folder 375)
  - Public Appearances in the USA, 1937-1963 (Box 25, Folder 376)
  - Lists of Scores & Recordings in Yale Music Library (Box 25, Folder 377)
  - H. Strobel: Paul Hindemith, a biography, translated by L. Noss (Box 25, Folder 378)
  - G. Schubert: HINDEMITH, pub. Rowohlt Taschenbuch Verlag, Hamburg, translated & condensed by L. Noss, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 379)
  - Documentary History of Paul Hindemith at Yale; Letters & Documents relating to Paul Hindemith's Yale appointment (Box 26, Folder 380)
  - Writings, Lectures, Speeches deposited in Hindemith Institute, Frankfurt, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 381)
  - Summary of Compositions; Recommended Listening List (Box 26, Folder 382)
  - Chronological Listings of Works (compositions, texts, speeches, etc.) Part I (1913-1933); Part II (1934-1963), 1982 (Box 26, Folder 383)
  - Establishment of the Foundation, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 384)
  - L. Noss Correspondence with the Hindemith Foundation, Frankfurt, 1971-78 (Box 26, Folder 385)
  - L. Noss Correspondence with the Hindemith Foundation, Frankfurt, 1978-93 (Box 26, Folder 386)
  - Concert Tours 1937, 1938, 1939, reprints from Jahrbuch VII/78; Paul Hindemith's First Seven Months in the USA (Box 26, Folder 387)
  - Publication Catalogues from Associated Music Publishers, Inc., New York (AMP)/Schott (Box 26, Folder 388)
  - Composition Listings (Box 26, Folder 389)
    - Composition Listings from G. Lam, 1965
    - Listing of Marches in various compositions, 1966
    - Composition Listing from Rexroth/Foundation, 1975
  - Composer lists (Box 26, Folder 390)
    - BMI List of Most-Often Performed Composers, 1969
    - Stanford University Survey of Top-50 Composers, 1965
  - Yale Oral History Project - Caitriona Bolster (Box 27, Folder 391)
  - Paul Hindemith Collection Summary (Box 27, Folder 392)
    - Kurt Stone's gift, 1988
    - Microfilm Reel No. 1 Index comprising correspondence, Yale documents, index to musical/literary works mentioned, 1988